At Free America, we've done a listening and learning tour.
في حملة أمريكا الحرة، قمنا بجولات استماع وتعلّم.
We visited not only with prosecutors
قمنا بزيارات ليس مع النواب العامين فقط
but with legislators,
بل حتى المشرّعين،
with inmates in our state and local prisons.
ونزلاء من سجون ولايتنا والسجون المحلية.
We've gone to immigration detention centers.
ذهبنا إلى مراكز احتجاز المهاجرين.
We've met a lot of people.
وقابلنا العديد من الناس.
And we've seen that redemption and transformation can happen
لمسنا أن الخلاص والتغيير ممكن الحدوث
in our prisons, our jails and our immigration detention centers,
في سجوننا ومعتقلاتنا ومراكزنا لاحتجاز المهاجرين.
giving hope to those who want to create a better life
مما يعطي أملا لهؤلاء الذين يودون بدأ حياة أفضل
after serving their time.
بعد قضائهم لمدة محكوميتهم.
Imagine if we also considered the front end of this prison pipeline.
تخيلوا لو أننا وضعنا في الاعتبار نقطة نهاية خط أنابيب السجن هذا.
What would it look like if we intervened,
ما الذي سيبدو عليه الأمر إن تدخلنا،
with rehabilitation as a core value --
بإعادة التأهيل كقيمة أساسية،
with love and compassion as core values?
وبالحب والشفقة كقيم أساسية كذلك؟
We would have a society that is safer,
سوف نحصل على مجتمع أكثر أماناً،
healthier
أكثر صحة
and worthy of raising our children in.
وجدير بتربية أبناءنا فيه.
I want to introduce you to James Cavitt.
أود أن أعرفكم على (جايمس كافيت).
James served 12 years in the San Quentin State Prison
قضى (جايمس) 12 عاما في سجن ولاية سان كوينتن
and is being released in 18 months.
وأطلق سراحه منذ 18 شهرا.
Now James, like you and me,
(جايمس) الآن مثلي ومثلكم،
is more than the worst thing he's done.
هو أفضل من أسوء شيء فعله.
He is a father, a husband, a son, a poet.
هو أب وزوج وابن وشاعر.
He committed a crime;
ارتكب جريمة،
he's paying his debt,
وهو يدفع دينه الآن،
and working hard to build the skills
ويعمل جاهداً لبناء المهارات
to make the transition back to a productive life
التي تسهل له العودة إلى الحياة المنتجة
when he enters the civilian population again.
عندما يندمج مع السكان المدنيين مجدداً.
Now James, like millions of people behind bars,
(جايمس) الآن كالملايين خلف القضبان،
is an example of what happens
مثال لما يمكن أن يحدث
if we believe that our failings don't define who we are,
إن آمنا أن عيوبنا لا تظهر معدننا الحقيقي،
that we are all worthy of redemption
وأننا جميعاً نستحق الخلاص
and if we support those impacted by mass incarceration,
وإذا ما دعمنا من يعانون من الحبس الشامل،
we can all heal together.
سيتسنى لنا التعافي جميعاُ.
I'd like to introduce you to James right now,
أود أن أقدم لكم (جايمس) الآن،
and he's going to share his journey of redemption
وسيشارككم رحلته نحو الخلاص
through spoken word.
عبر كلمات مقروءة.
James Cavitt: Thanks, John.
جايمس كافيت: شكراً يا جون.
TED, welcome to San Quentin.
TED أهلا بكم في سان كوينتن.
The talent is abundant behind prison walls.
مواهب خلاقة خلف جدران السجن هذه.
Future software engineers,
مهندسو برمجيات المستقبل،
entrepreneurs,
رواد أعمال،
craftsmen,
حرفييون،
musicians
موسيقييون
and artists.
وفنانون.
This piece is inspired by all of the hard work
هذه القطعة مستلهمة من العمل الجبار
that men and women are doing on the inside
الذي يقوم به هؤلاء الرجال والنساء بالداخل
to create better lives and futures for themselves
لخلق حياة ومستقبل أفضل لنفسهم
after they serve their time.
بعد قضاء مدة محكوميتهم.
This piece is entitled, "Where I Live."
هذه القطعة عنوانها، "حيث أعيش."
I live in a world where most people are too afraid to go.
أنتمي لعالم يخشى زيارته الجميع.
Surrounded by tall, concrete walls,
محاطا بجدران خرسانية عالية،
steel bars,
وقضبان فولاذية،
where razor wire have a way
حيث تبرع الأسلاك الشائكة
of cutting away at the hopes for a brighter tomorrow.
في قطع طريق أحلامنا نحو غد أكثر إشراقاً.
I live in a world
أعيش في عالم
that kill people who kill people
يقتل القاتل
in order to teach people
ليعطي الآخرين درسا
that killing people is wrong.
بأن قتل الناس خطأ.
Imagine that.
تخيل معي.
Better yet,
بل أفضل من ذلك،
imagine a world where healed people helped hurt people heal
تخيل عالماً يداوي فيه من تعافى جراح المرضى ليتعافَوا.
and become strong.
ليصبحوا أقوى.
Maybe then we would all be singin' "Redemption Song."
حينها قد نغني جميعاً "أغنية الخلاص".
I live in a world that has been called "hell on Earth"
أعيش في عالم سمي "جحيم على الأرض"
by those trapped inside.
كما أطلق عليه السجناء بداخله.
But I've come to the stark realization
لكنني الآن أدرك تماما
that prison --
أن ذاك السجن--
it really is what you make it.
هو ما تريده أن يكون.
You see, in spite of the harshness of my reality,
كما ترون، على الرغم من قسوة واقعي،
there is a silver lining.
لا يزال هناك جانب مضيء.
I knew that my freedom was gonna come,
عرفت أنني سأنال حريتي،
it was just a matter of time.
المسألة مسألة وقت فقط.
And so I treated my first steps as if they were my last mile,
لذلك بدأت خطواتي الأولى وكأنها الأخيرة.
and I realized that you don't have to be free
وأدركت أنك لست بحاجة أن تكون حراً
in order to experience freedom.
لتشعر بالحرية.
And just because you're free,
فكونك حر،
doesn't mean that you have freedom.
لا يعني أنك تملك الحرية.
Many of us, for years, have been battling our inner demons.
لسنين، خضنا صراعا داخليا مع نفسنا الأمارة بالسوء.
We walk around smiling when inside we're really screamin':
تعلو وجوهنا بسمة بينما نصرخ من الداخل.
freedom!
الحرية!
Don't you get it?
ألم تفهمها؟
We're all serving time;
جميعنا أصحاب أحكام،
we're just in different places.
أماكننا مختلفة لا غير.
As for me,
بالنسة لي،
I choose to be free from the prisons I've created.
اخترت التحرر من سجونٍ اختلقتها.
The key:
مفتاحي،
forgiveness.
هو التسامح.
Action's my witness.
والعمل هو شاهدي.
If we want freedom,
إن أردنا الحرية،
then we gotta think different.
علينا أن نغير تفكيرنا.
Because freedom ...
لأن الحرية...
it isn't a place.
ليست مكانا.
It's a mind setting.
إنها برمجة عقلية.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
(Piano)
(بيانو)
John Legend: Old pirates, yes, they rob I.
(جون ليجيند): نعم لقد سلبني القراصنة القدامى.
Sold I to the merchant ships.
باعوني للسفن التجارية.
Minutes after they took I
بعدما ان انتشلوني بدقائق
from the bottomless pit.
من الهاوية.
My hands were made strong
يداي قويتان
by the hand of the almighty.
بقدرة يد الإله القادر
We forward in this generation
نحن نتقدم بهذا الجيل
triumphantly.
منتصرين.
Won't you help to sing
ألن تغني؟
these songs of freedom?
أغاني الحرية هذه؟
'Cause all I ever had --
فهي كل ما كنت أملك حينها--
redemption songs.
أغاني الخلاص.
Emancipate yourselves from mental slavery.
اعتقوا أنفسكم من العبودية العقلية.
None but ourselves can free our minds.
لن يحرر عقولنا غيرنا.
Have no fear for atomic energy
لا تخافوا اللطاقة الذرية
'cause none of them can stop the time.
فلا أحد منهم يستطيع إيقاف الزمن.
How long shall they kill our prophets
إلى متى سيقتلون أنبياءنا
while we stand aside and look?
بينما نحن وقوف ننظر؟
Some say it's just a part of it,
يقولون إنه جزء فقط.
we've got to fulfill the book.
لابد من أن ننجز الكتاب.
Won't you help to sing
ألن تغني؟
these songs of freedom?
أغاني الحرية هذه؟
'Cause all I ever had --
لأن كل ما كنت أملك حينها--
redemption songs.
أغاني الخلاص.
(Piano)
(بيانو)
Emancipate yourselves from mental slavery.
أعتقوا أنفسكم من العبودية العقلية
None but ourselves can free our minds.
لن يحرر عقولنا أحد سوانا
Have no fear for atomic energy
لا تخافواالطاقة الذرية
'cause none of them can stop the time.
فلا أحد منهم يستطيع إيقاف الزمن.
How long shall they kill our prophets
إلى متى سيقتلون أنبياءنا
while we stand aside and look?
بينما نحن وقوف ننظر؟
Some say it's just a part of it,
يقولون إنه جزء فقط،
we've got to fulfill the book.
لابد أن ننجزالكتاب.
Won't you help to sing
ألن تغني؟
these songs of freedom?
أغاني الحرية هذه؟
'Cause all I ever had --
لأن كل ما كنت أملك حينها--
redemption songs.
أغاني الخلاص.
These songs of freedom.
أغاني الحرية هذه.
'Cause all I ever had --
لأن كل ما كنت أملك حينها--
redemption songs.
أغاني الخلاص.
(Piano)
(بيانو)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.